hi and welcome back to new every day my
こんにちは、 私の新しい毎日に ようこそ 私の
name is Carrie and my name is Chen and
名前はキャリーで、私の名前はチェンと
on today's show up and talk about what
今日の ショーで
is if it'll make you Malik stay tuned
あなたがMalikを調整してくれるかどうかです
welcome back love that you've tuned in
あなたが調整した愛を歓迎する
again to new every day we sure hope that
再び毎日新しいものにすることを願っています
you're checking out our website new
私たちのウェブサイトを チェックアウトし ています新しい
everyday TV did see the the newest
毎日のテレビが最新のものを見た
posting to check out our partners pages
パートナーのページをチェックするための投稿
click partners the link at the top of
クリックパートナーのトップにあるリンク
the page you can see all the wonderful
あなたはすばらしいすべてを見ることができるページ
people we have supporting us and the
私たちが私たちを支えている人々と
wonderful organizations so check them
すばらしい組織だから
out our partners page at new everyday TV
毎日新しいテレビでパートナーのページを出す
and how are you not bad it's the end of
どのように悪くないのですか？
the day we we went exploring today we
私たちが今日探検する日
don't do it very often because you're
非常に多くの場合、あなたがしているので、それを しません
going to start thinking wow those girls
それらの女の子を考え始めるつもり
travel a lot and well relatively yes but
多くの旅行をしています。
you only see the traveling yeah but
あなたは唯一の旅行ええを参照してください
there's a lot of days in between we're
私たちの間には多くの日があります
not traveling but today we actually had
旅行はしていませんが、今日は実際に
a day where it's like oh we're both home
ああ、私たちは両方の家にいるような一日
why don't we go to the Y marsh and so
なぜ私たちはY沼に行くのではないのですか？
today we went to this place called the
今日私たちはこの場所に行った
the Y marsh Conservation Center yes for
Y 湿地保全センターはい
the purpose in Midland Ontario yes for
オンタリオ州ミッドランドの目的は
the purpose of walking through the snow
雪を歩く目的
snowshoeing and holding chickadees in
スノーシューイングとチキン
our hands and that was the real purpose
私たちの手とそれは本当の目的でした
of going but it's about 45 minutes away
行くのは約 45分です
from where we live and we just simply
私たちがどこに住んでいるのか
said we want to be outside we want to go
私たちが外に出たいと言った
snowshoeing but ultimately we want to
スノーシューイングですが、最終的には
hold chickadees in our hands oh yeah
私たちの手の中でchickadeesを保持するああええ
every winter my family and I made a
毎冬私の家族と私は
point of going there so we could either
そこに行くことのポイント
cross-country ski and feed them I can
クロスカントリースキーをして、私はそれを食べることができます
feed them snowshoe and feed them there's
スノーシューを食べ、そこに食べさせる
just something so beautiful about
ただ とても美しいもの
holding this little creature in your
この小さな生き物をあなたの中に入れて
hand and it just trusts you in comes and
手に入れて、あなたを信じて
sits and you feel it so cute it is one
座って、あなたはそれがとてもかわいい と感じる
of them really just want to hold it 10
彼らは本当にただそれを 保持し たい 10
might not have felt like doing that but
それをするような気がしなかったかもしれません
anyways they land and then they take the
とにかく彼らは土地を取得し、その後彼らは
food and they flutter away and you can
食べ物と彼らは離れてひらひらとすることができます
hear their wings and then you can hear
彼らの翼を聞いて聞くことができます
them tap tap tapping the seeds to open
彼らはタップタップタップシードを開くには
them up and it's just so beautiful and
それらをアップし、それはちょうどとても美しいです
every time I go my heart is so full
私が行くたびに私の心はとても満ちている
holding these birds because I feel like
私のような気がするので、これらの鳥を保持
it's just such a wonderful picture of
それは
trust that the chickadees will come to
チカデーが来ると信じて
us we're so much bigger than that I
私たち、私たちはそのため、私よりもはるかに大きいです
could just go like that and catch it and
ちょうどそのように行くと、それをキャッチでき、
hurt
傷つける
it I would never do that I understood
それは私が理解することは決してしません
that when they're little boys would know
彼らは少年時代は知っているだろう
hurt the told sir des it just hated that
それを嫌っていたことを傷つけた
and it was such a beautiful picture of
それはとても美しい写真でした
trust and provision at the same time
同時に信用と提供
knowing that she's thought about that
彼女はそれについて考えていることを知っている
and doesn't do it makes me happy see I'm
そしてそれは私を幸せにしない
not going to squeeze the sweet little
甘いものを絞るつもりはない
thing for real oh alright yes do it I
本当のための事 大丈夫はいはい私はそれをする
totally enjoyed it I do I i love the
それを完全に楽しんだ
fact that you put these seeds in the
あなたがこれらの種子を
hand and the birds come and they have
手と鳥が来て、彼らは持っている
been around people enough that you're
あなたの 周りに いて
right they do trust them they trust the
彼らは信頼している
fact that those seeds are safe and that
それらの種子は安全であり、
you know they can come and eat them fly
あなたは彼らが来て食べることができることを知っている
off and everything's good and what we're
オフ、 すべての 良いと 私たちがしています
talking about the big question day is is
大きな質問の日について話すのは、
what what is it that will make you
何があなたを作るだろうか
believe yeah now for those birds they
それらの鳥のために今ええ信じる
have overtime been convinced that people
残業を人々に納得させました
are safe that like they've never met us
彼らは私たちに会ったことがないように安全です
before they've never seen this before
前にこれを見たことがない前に
and yet going through this one part of
まだこの1つの部分を
the hike it's like one of the chickadees
ハイキングはチカダイの一つのようなものです
literally came and stood in front of us
文字通り来て、私たちの前に立った
like only to say put your hand out yeah
あなたの手をええと言うだけのように
I think like a more like did you not
私はもっ​​とあなたのように思った
feel like the pressure well see i think
プレッシャーのような気分だ
it was cuz you were doing your tickity
それはあなたの 忠実な ことをしていたcuzだった
call chickadee dddddd but i hadn't
chickadee ddddddを呼び出すが、 私はなかった
actually said it yet like we got to that
実際に、我々はそれに得たように、まだそれを言いました
point and they looked and I'm like oh
ポイントと彼らは見て、私はああのようだ
both of us were like ooh we know what to
私たちの両方は、私たちは何を知っている
do and they knew it and they knew it so
彼らはそれを知っていて、彼らはそれを知っていた
over time the trust has been built up
時間が経つと信託が築かれた
people are safe if i look at them or if
私がそれらを見るならば、人々は安全です。
they called to me right it's that whole
彼らは私に右にそれを呼んだ
conditioned response but they believe
調整された反応を信じている
that people are safe and that will feed
人々は安全であり、それは餌になるだろう
them and so when we talk about what is
彼らとは何か について話すとき
it that would make you believe the
それ はあなたを信じさせるでしょう
question is what is it that make you
質問はあなたを
believe in god yeah and we're asking
神様を信じて、私たちは
that question because we're heading into
私たちが
Easter and so in the in the book of John
イースターと同様に、ジョンの本
The Passion Week starts about John 12
受難週間はジョン12について始まります
with the triumphant entry
勝利のエントリーと
and as we were reading beforehand and
事前に読んでいた
preparing Carrie came across an
キャリーの準備は、
interesting part of the passage so I
面白い部分のように私は
just would ask her to read it yeah it's
ちょうど彼女にそれを読んで頼むだろう
in John 12 and it's actually verse 37
ジョン12でそれは実際には37節です
and the context to this first is that
この最初の文脈は、
Jesus beforehand in the previous chapter
イエスは前の章で前もって
chapter 11 had just raised Lazarus from
第11章では、ラザロを
the dead like performed this amazing
死んだようなこの素晴らしい実行
miracle and people were coming from far
奇跡と人々は遠くから来ていた
and wide and Pharisees were also coming
また、広大なパリサイ人たちも来ていた
to not only see Jesus but to look at
イエスを見るだけでなく、見ること
Lazarus the one who raised from the dead
ラザロ死んだ者から甦った者
to see like is this for real did this
本当にこれが本当ですか？
actually happen they wanted to see
実際に彼らが見たいと思って起こった
interact with them and there's the
それらと交流し、
interesting verse is verse 37 but
面白い詩は37節ですが
although he had done so many signs
彼は非常に多くの兆候を見せていた
before them they did not believe in him
彼らの前に彼らは彼を信じなかった
that the word of Isaiah the prophet
預言者イザヤの言葉
might be fulfilled which she spoke Lord
彼女が主に話したことが成就するかもしれない
who has believed our report and to whom
誰が私たちの報告を信じているのか
has the arm of the Lord been revealed so
主の腕が明らかにされている
even though he had done this amazing
彼がこの素晴らしいことをしたにもかかわらず
miracle they still didn't believe mm-hmm
彼らはまだ信じられなかった奇跡mm-hmm
and sometimes you know I think well what
時には私は よく 考えて いることを知っ ている
what what's going to be the tipping
何がチップになるのか
point for people that they're going to
彼らが行く人のためのポイント
say you know what there is a God or
あなたが神があるか、または
Jesus really is the son of God you know
イエスは本当にあなたが 知っている神の息子です
or maybe they need some kind of miracle
あるいは彼らは何らかの奇跡を必要とするかもしれない
in their life maybe they need to be
彼らの人生では
healed of something maybe they need to
彼らが必要とするかもしれない何かを治癒
see and written across the sky but what
空を見渡すが、何を
is more dramatic than seeing someone
誰かを見るよりも劇的です
raised from the dead we were also
私たちはまた死者から育った
talking earlier about how like people
どのように人々のように早く話す
who they receive some kind of radical
彼らは何人か過激派を受ける
medical intervention and kind of get a
医療介入と種類の取得
new lease on life how their perspective
人生における新しいリース
is totally different to a change like
のような変化と全く違う
I've got a second chance and and and
私は2度目のチャンスを得ました。
they often realize yeah God has given
彼らはしばしば、 神が与えた
this to me it's God who has done this
これは私にはこれをやったのは神だ
but even these people saw him raised
しかし、これらの人々でさえ、
from the dead that still was not enough
まだ十分ではなかった死人から
to believe mm-hmm and we were talking
信じるにはmm-hmmと話していた
today is how I was holding the
今日は、私が持っていた方法です
chickadees and it makes me think of the
chickadeesと私はそれを考えさせる
first it says you open your hand and
まず、あなたの手を開いて
satisfy the desires of every living
あらゆる生活の欲望を満たす
thing and God provides miraculously for
物と神は奇跡的に
each ecosystem in the war
戦争の各生態系
old so you look at diversity in the
あなたは多様な
ocean and how there's plankton is
プランクトンはどうですか？
something that needs blanked in it and
そこに空白を入れる必要があるもの
you you look at how some things are just
あなたは、いくつかのことがちょうどどのように見えるか
so diverse and yet God I was taking care
とても多様でありながら、私は世話をしていました
of individual needs and he feeds each
個々のニーズの
one and it's so amazing and the
それはとても驚くべきことです
privilege that we had to feed these
私たちがこれらの栄養を与えなければならなかった特権
creatures and the joy that I got of
私が得た生き物と喜び
holding them that I think God loves to
私は神が愛すると思っている
provide for us he loves to open his hand
私たちのために彼は彼の手を開くのが大好き
and satisfy our desires and our needs
私たちの欲望とニーズを満たす
and that for me seeing how God provides
そして、神がどのようにして
seeing biodiversity seeing the
生物多様性を見て
complexity of nature and how it all
自然の複雑さとそのすべて
works together in this fine-tuned
この微調整で一緒に働く
machine was a stepping stone in building
機械は建物の踏み台だった
my faith in rice in God what was there
神の中の米に対する私の信仰そこにあったもの
something in your life Jen that made you
あなたの人生の何かJenがあなたを作った
I know that you came to Christ when you
私はあなたがキリストに来たことを知っています。
were quite young but was there have
かなり若かったが、そこにあった
there been points along the way where
途中でポイントがあった
you're like yeah that just reaffirmed my
あなたはちょうど私のことを再確認したようなものです
faith or yeah that was a real check
本当の小切手だった信仰かええ
point in my life it's a great question
それは大きな問題です
usually it's a daily thing like it's a
通常は毎日のようなものです
daily Wow God like you you answered that
毎日あなたがあなたのように答えた
prayer Wow you answered you answer that
祈りあなたはそれに答えると答えた
prayer okay you answered that prayer
祈り大丈夫あなたはその祈りに答えました
again yeah and so for me that you know
もう一度ええ、 私のためにあなたが知っている
what is it going to take you to believe
あなたは何を信じるのだろう？
it's more of an ongoing okay you are
それは進行中のあなたの大丈夫です
real yeah okay you you are real okay you
本当のええ、あなたは本当に大丈夫ですか？
did hear me and so you know when you
私のことを聞いていたので、あなたが
read this passage and what is it you
この通路を読んで、あなたは何ですか？
know what is it that's going to take it
それがそれを取るつもりであることを知っている
take you to a point where you choose to
あなたが選択するポイントにあなたを連れて行く
believe I think sometimes some of the
時には
arguments that I have heard is well if I
私が聞いた議論は、もし私が
choose to believe then that means i have
それを信じることを選ぶことは、私が
to give up everything right right yeah
すべての権利を諦める
and so it's much easier to discount
それで割引の方がはるかに簡単です
truth then choose to live it and you
真実はそれから生きることを選ぶ
know that asks something of you because
あなたの何かを尋ねることを知っているから
it asks something of it and i often
それは何かと私は頻繁に尋ねる
think of ravi zacharias and how he goes
ravi zachariasと彼のやり方について考える
up
アップ
how he goes up against all the different
彼がどう違う
I want to say leading atheists of the
私は、
world right I'll who are anti God and
世界の権利私は誰が反神であり、
you know they're trying to disprove the
あなたは、彼らが反証しようとしているのを知っています
existence of god and raava Ravi is is
神と ラヴァの存在ラヴィは
proving the existence of God and I'm
神の存在を証明すると私は
listening and the truth just sounds so
聞くと 真実はちょうどそう聞く
clear but that's might be because I
それは私が
believe the truth it was news player to
それはニュースプレイヤーだった真実を信じて
you so it seems clear to me and on the
あなたは私にとって、そして
other side to prove that God doesn't
神がそうでないことを証明するための反対側
exist just I like really so when you
あなただけが本当に好きなだけ存在する
look at the world and that's what Roman
世界を見て、 それはローマ
says right it says his well let me just
そうだよ
turn to its Romans 120 or something like
そのローマ人のようなものに変えなさい。
that I'm going to use my techie Bible my
私は自分のテキサー聖書を使用するつもりです私は
pages are sticking together because it
ページは
says Romans 119 since what may be known
何が知られているかもしれないので
about God is plain to them because God
神様は神様ですから
has made a plain to them for since the
それ以来のために彼らに平野を作った
creation of the world God's invisible
世界の創造神の目に見えない
qualities his eternal power and divine
彼の永遠の力と神の資質
nature have been clearly seen being
自然がはっきりと見えている
understood from what has been made so
理解されたことから理解される
that men are without excuse so creation
人はそのような言い訳がないので
should testify that there is a God yeah
ええ 、神がいると証言するはずだ
and Psalm 19 says the heavens declare
詩編19章には天国が宣言しています
the glory of God the skies proclaim the
神の栄光が空を宣言する
work of his hands day after day they
日々の彼の手の仕事
pour forth speech night after night date
夜の日の後にスピーチの夜を注ぐ
they reveal God's knowledge yes yeah we
彼らは神の知識を明らかにする
can see it all around us yeah and so you
私たちの周りのすべてそれを見ることができますええとあなた
know i do i do believe that God exists
私は神が存在すると信じるのですか？
by looking at nature but also through
自然を見ながらも
personal experience I've seen answers to
個人的な経験私は答えを見た
prayer that were not coincidental okay I
偶然ではない祈り大丈夫
have you know like physical answers to
あなたは物理的な答えのように知っている
prayer raining what do you mean by like
祈りの雨 あなたの好きなことは 何 ですか？
physical like in my body physical or
物理的な私の体のような物理的な
like like
のような
well I guess I was going to say not like
まあ、 私は好きでは ないと言う つもりだっ たと思います
it an emotional thing right like God's
それは神のような感情的なことです
provision for you
あなたのための準備
hmm when have I seen answers to prayer
うーん、いつ私は祈りの答えを見た
well we'll let you know when we come
私たちが来るときにあなたに知らせるでしょう
back stay tuned hi I'm Robbie Ferguson
私はロビー・ファーガソンです。
and I love being a vimeo pro member as a
私はvimeoプロのメンバーであることが大好きです
web broadcaster i need an affordable
ウェブ放送局私は手頃な価格が必要
video hosting platform that's as
ビデオホスティングプラットフォーム
flexible as me a pro membership lets you
柔軟な私のプロメンバーシップはあなたに
upload up to 20 gigabytes of HD video
最大20ギガバイトのHDビデオをアップロード
each and every week with no additional
毎週、追加なしで
bandwidth restrictions that means if you
帯域幅の制限 は、あなたが
produce a show that uses even up to 20
最大20のショーを制作する
gigabytes of storage your limit resets
リミットがリセットされるストレージのギガバイト
itself the following week so you can do
次の週にあなた自身が行うことができます
another 20 gigabytes and keep doing that
別の20ギガバイトとそれを続けて
week after week now category 5 with all
毎週今週カテゴリ5、すべて
of our shows use roughly 10 gigabytes
私たちのショーのおよそ10ギガバイト
per week from there vimeo automatically
そこから一週間にvimeoが自動的に
generates all the files that you need to
あなたが必要とするすべてのファイルを生成する
provision your RSS feeds roku channel
RSSフィードのrokuチャンネルをプロビジョニングする
website media player or even video
ウェブサイトのメディアプレーヤーまたはビデオ
downloads in multiple bit rates with no
複数のビットレートでダウンロードする
limits on your bandwidth usage or how
帯域幅の使用量や制限について
many people can access your files what's
多くの人があなたのファイルにアクセスできます
best the price is astonishingly
最高の価格は驚くほどです
affordable and for a limited time
手頃な価格と限られた時間
friends of the category 5 TV network
カテゴリ5のテレビネットワークの友人
will receive a whopping twenty-five
はるかに25
percent off the annual price all you
すべてのあなたの年間価格のパーセント
have to do is go through our link cat
私たちのリンクcatを通過する必要があります
five dot TV / vimeo and sign up today
5つのドットテレビ/ vimeoと今日サインアップ
for your twenty five percent discount to
あなたの25％の割引は
top it off you get 30 days to try it
それ を試してみる のに 30日かかる
risk-free if you're not happy with vimeo
あなたがvimeoに満足していないなら、リスクフリー
pro you pay nothing the deal is only for
あなたは何を支払う必要はありませんプロ契約はわずかです
a very limited time go to cat five dot
非常に限られた時間が猫の5つのドットに行く
TV / vimeo welcome back to new every day
TV / vimeoは毎日 新しい 日に歓迎され ています
Jen you're just going to share a story
Jenあなたはただの話を分かち合うつもりです
of how God had provided for you
神があなたのために提供した方法の
was kind of an affirmation again of your
あなたのことをもう一度確信していた
faith in him I wasn't know you were no I
彼の信仰は、私はあなたが何も私ではなかった知っていませんでした
was gonna say how I answer prayer yeah
どのように私は祈りに答えると言うつもり だった
not how he provided me wine it was like
彼が私にワインを提供した方法ではない
that was the previous conversation but
以前の会話だった
no this one was about answered prayer
これは答えられた祈りに関するものではありません
like I don't think I can work that one
私はその1つ を 働かせるとは思わない
around you're pretty skilled with words
あなたの周りは言葉にかなり熟練しています
but it's a long long shot let's try that
それは長い試行ですが、それを試してみましょう
again Jen before we took that break you
もう一度Jen私たちがあなたを壊す前に
were just about to say how God answers
ちょうど神がどのように答えているかを言っていた
prayer right how I know that God has
私は神が持っていることを知っている
answered prayer yeah and it's
答えられた祈りとそれは
interesting because it usually comes
それは通常来るので面白い
about when when people where I've prayed
いつ私が祈ったのか
for someone and then they will message
誰かのために彼らはメッセージになります
me or tell me face face to face Jen you
私に話すか、ジェンに面接してください
prayed for me and this happened oh yeah
私のために祈って、これはああええ起こった
so it's through someone else oh yeah and
だから、それは誰か他の人がええオハイオ州と
it's happened enough now where I go and
それは私が行く場所で今起こっています
it sort of gets and that reminds me that
それは一種の取得し、それがあること を思い出します
God hey here's my prayers yeah because
神様ねえ、ええ、私の祈り だから。
it isn't the same person coming and
来る人と同じ人ではない
telling me all the time it's different
それが違うときはいつも教えて
people in different areas of my life who
私の人生のさまざまな分野の人々
have said you prayed for me and this
あなたと私のために祈ってくれた
happened and I was like wow he does hear
起こったと私は彼が聞くうわーのようだった
me Wow he does answer prayer now there
私はうわー、彼は今そこに祈りをしている
have been times where I've had difficult
私が難しかった時代
conversations to have it i'm just like
私はちょうど好きです
dear lord please help me and then wow he
親愛なる主よ、私を助けてください
goes before he prepares the way and I
彼は道を準備する前に行くと私は
come out going Wow God that went
うわー、行く神が出てくる
surprisingly well you were good and now
驚いたことにあなたは元気だった
a friend of mine uh Susan zerk assess me
私の友人Susan zerkが私を評価する
all the time she's like Jen you just
彼女はいつもジェンのようなものだ
pray your way out of everything but
すべてのことからあなたの道を祈る
that's because I actually honestly
それは私が実際に正直に言って
believe that someone's on the other end
誰かが反対側にいると信じて
of my prayers like someone is on the
誰かのような私の祈りの
other end of my prayers listening so
それを聞いている私の祈りの他の終わり
when we talk about what is it going to
それが何になるのか話し合うとき
take for you to believe I've had enough
私が 十分 に持っていたと信じて
experience I guess for me now it's
経験私は 今、それは私のためだと思います
experience where God has said see I did
神が私がやったことを私が見たと言った経験
it again see I did it again see I did it
もう一度やったことを見ます
again and so I've also seen like life
再び私は人生のように見えた
change in people okay I know you've seen
人々の変化大丈夫私はあなたが見たことを知っている
life change in people where you just go
あなたが行ったばかりの人々の人生の変化
oh okay yeah you wouldn't have done that
ああ大丈夫ですね
on your own no or that response you just
あなた自身の答えではありません。
gave is was not yourself it's because of
与えられたのはあなたのためではありませんでした
a transformed life in Christ yeah and I
キリストの変容した人生と私
even found my bad about myself yeah like
私の ような 私の悪いことを見つけた
wow God like you let me say that you let
うわー、あなたのように、私が あなたに
me not say that more importantly right
私はもっ​​と重要なのはそれが正しいとは言いません
you know which goes to actually reaffirm
どちらが実際に再確認されるのか分かります
why we believe right like it's like we
なぜ我々はそれが私たちのようなものだ右のように信じています
we originally believed because while I
私たちはもともと私が信じていた
was raised in the church but it just all
教会で育てられましたが、それだけです
started to make sense and I was having
理にかなって始めていた
my own experiences of God and so but you
私自身の神様の体験など
came to faith differently but also
別に信仰にも来ましたが、
through experience and watching it
経験を通してそれを見て
happen and God working in your own life
起こって、あなたの人生で働く神
and like yeah so so we've had our
ええ、 私たちは
experience and then we've had
経験をしてから
reaffirming experience ago okay this is
前に経験を再確認する
why I believe yeah this is why I believe
なぜ私は信じているのですか？
and yet you know the passage that were
それでも、あなたは
we're looking at the men are saying
私たちは男性が言っているのを見ている
Jesus is saying they're not going to
イエスは彼らに行くつもりはないと言っている
believe like even though even though
たとえ
they saw this sign yeah like even though
彼らはこのサインを見た
he raised Lazarus from the dead it's not
彼は死者の中からラザロを育てた
going to be enough for you yeah now you
あなたは今あなたのために十分になるだろう
wanted you wanted to share a passage of
あなたが一節を共有したいと思った
a parable that Jesus gave yes it is
イエスがそれを与えたという寓話です
actually in Luke 16 and it starts first
実際にはルカ16で始まり、最初に始まります
19 and it's called the rich man and
19、 それは富豪と呼ばれています
Lazarus this is a different Lazarus but
ラザロこれは別のラザロですが、
to paraphrase the story there was a very
物語を言い換えれば、非常に
rich man and there was a beggar named
金持ちの男と名前の乞食があった
Lazarus who was full of sores and laid
荒れ果てて倒れたラザロ
at the gate of the of the rich man like
金持ちの人の門 のように
outside his big mansion essentially a
彼の大邸宅の外では本質的に
knee and the the beggar was desiring to
膝と乞食は望んでいた
be fed with the crumbs which fell from
から落ちたクラムを食べる
the rich man's table and the dogs came
裕福な男のテーブルと犬が来た
and licked his sores so one day the
彼の痛みを一日のうちに舐めた。
beggar dies the Lazarus died and he and
乞食は死んだラザロと彼と
he was carried by angels to Abraham's
彼は天使たちによってアブラハムに運ばれた
bosom the rich man also died and was
金持ちも死んでいた
buried and the rich man goes to Hades
埋葬され、金持ちはハデスに行く
like a hell type place right and he was
地獄型のように
able to see Lazarus from where he was
彼 が どこから来たのかを見ることができます
and saw that he was in peace but he was
彼が平和であることを見たが、彼は
that the rich man was in torment
金持ちが苦しんでいたこと
any e says to Abraham area I'm like I
どんな電子もアブラハムのエリアに言う私は私のようだ
have please send Lazarus to my brothers
ラザロを私の兄弟たちに送ってください
and my father so that they don't have to
彼らは私の父に 持た ないように、
come to this place that they can
彼らができるこの場所に来る
experience the peace of God like I
私のように神の平和を体験する
didn't turn listen you know I don't not
私は知らない
going to add words to Scripture but
聖書に言葉を追加するつもりですが
anyways essentially saying please send
とにかく本質的に言ってください
this man yeah because if they see a guy
この男ええ、 もし彼らが男を見たら
who was raised from the dead maybe
死者の中から育てられた人
they'll believe yeah he says no father
彼らは父がいないと言っていると信じるでしょう
Abraham if one goes to them from the
もしアブラハムが彼らから
dead then they will repent but he said
死んだら、 彼らは悔い改めますが、彼は言った
to him if they do not hear Moses and the
彼らに モーセと
prophets neither will they be persuaded
預言者は説得されない
the one rise from the dead and when
死者からの一人の上昇といつ
Jesus was speaking to the people he said
イエスは彼が言った人々に話していた
one greater than Abraham is here one
アブラハムよりも大きなものがここにあります
greater than Moses is here he said you
モーセよりも大きいです
search the Scriptures because you think
あなたが考えるので、聖書を検索してください
that buy them they obtain life but these
それを買う人は人生を得ますが、これらは
are the scriptures that testify about me
私について証言する聖典です
and he was talking with the Old
彼は老人と話していた
Testament Jesus is in the old testament
聖書イエスは旧約聖書にあります
and in in the Book of Psalms it says the
そして詩篇の書には、
Word of God is perfect reviving or
神の言葉は完全に復活する
converting the soul essentially right so
本質的に正しいように魂を変換する
there's something living in active about
活発に何かが生きている
the Word of God and the Old Testament
神の言葉と旧約 聖書
that alludes to Christ and his saving
それはキリストと彼の貯蓄を暗示している
power and I think that God like can use
パワーと私は神のように使うことができる と思います
scripture to transform you and we should
あなたを変えるための聖句
be able to see Christ in Scripture it's
聖書の中でキリストを見ることができるようになる
just so interesting that even jesus said
ちょうどとても面白いので、イエスも
listen if people won't believe even
人々が信じられないかどうか聞いてください
though they see someone rise from the
彼らは誰かが
dead it won't be enough of a sign yeah
死んでもそれは十分なサインではありません
but God doesn't work in transforming
しかし、神は変容には働かない
people's hearts and drawing them to
人々の心をつかんで
himself and you said something
あなたと何かが言った
interesting about how God draws people
神が人をどのように引き付けるかについて興味深い
today right well it says it is kindness
今日はよくそれは優しさだと言う
that draws us right and he loves us he
それは私たちを右に引き寄せ、彼は私たちを愛しています
was us you even said he's the hound of
私たちは、あなたも彼はの猟犬だと述べました
heaven he purrs like he pursues us and
彼は私たちと
yet unless someone makes that willful
まだ誰かがそれを意図的にしない限り
choice and accepts that love then it's
選択とは、それはだ 、その愛を受け入れます
like it doesn't matter what would happen
何が起こるかは関係ありません
you're just simply not going to believe
あなたは単に信じ ないだろう
they make a willful choice not to
彼らは故意でない選択をする
believe and for me that's one of the
信じて、それは私の
like literally I don't know what to say
文字通り私は何を言うべきか分からない
about that when people just make a
人々はちょうど 作る 際にそのことについて
willful choice not to leave when the
故意の選択は、
evidence is there yeah and they're like
証拠はありますか？
no or oh yeah I can see where that's
いいえ、それはどこにあるのかわかります
true but I'm just not going to believe
本当ですが、私は信じるつもりはありません
it and it's like but it's truth yeah I
それはそれのようですが、 それは真実ええ私です
guess no I know I struggle with that
私はそれと闘うことを知っている
because the truth is just so clear and
真実はとても明確であり、
yet people continue to say no and I can
まだ人々はいいえと言い続けています。
understand the perspective you know some
あなたが知っている視点を理解する
of my friends who have gone through a B
Bを経た友達の
and C or who have had a bad experience
Cや悪い経験をしている人
in church and me and that's kind of like
教会と私とでは、それは一種です
put a bad taste in their mouth for God
神のために彼らの口に悪い味を置く
but he's been misrepresented by people
しかし、彼は人々によって誤解されている
who say that they knew him or say they
彼らは彼を知っていると言ったり、
were acting on his behalf so I kind of
彼のために行動していたので
get I get it where they're coming from
彼らはどこから来ているのか取得する
because our past history our emotions
私たちの過去の歴史、私たちの感情
whatever can kind of cloud our
どんなことでも雲が出ることができます
perspective where you know even we might
あなたが知っている視点
see someone who's risen from the dead
死者の中から起き上がった人を見なさい
and still do not believe but you know I
まだ信じていないけど、 あなたは私を知っている
think that faith is a gift of God and
信仰は神の賜物であると考えてください。
God draws us to himself and salvation
神は私たちを自分自身と救いに導きます
even if it was when you were young or
あなたが若かっ た時であったとしても
when you were older that it's a miracle
あなたが年を取った時、それは奇跡です
and to celebrate that in God and I just
神と私だけでそれを祝うために
look at you know some people in my own
あなた自身を見てください
family that I thought you know they
あなたが知っていると思った家族
would never believe in God they would
彼らが神を信じることは決してありません
never they've had the worst history that
彼らは最悪の歴史を持っていたことはありません
you know yeah been through so much and
あなたはそんなに多くのことを経験しています
you got in His grace has revealed
あなたは彼の恵みを手に入れた
himself to them I don't get it I don't
自分自身に私はそれを取得しない私はしない
get it because you can't earn it yeah
あなたがそれを得ることができないのでそれを得るええ
and so when you ask the question you
それであなたが質問したら
know what is it that were to help with
助けてくれるものが何かを知っている
that what is it that would make you
それはあなたを作るだろうか
believe maybe one of the questions is
おそらく質問の一つが
well what's holding you back from
あなたを元気にしてくれるもの
believing and so we're going to sign off
信じているからサインオフするつもりだ
now because it's that time but we want
その時だから今は望んでいるから
to leave you with that question what is
その質問をあなたに残すことは何ですか？
it that you know makes you believe or
あなたが知っていることは、あなたが
what is it that made you believe and
それはあなたを信じさせた
what is it that's tripping you up like
それはあなたのようにあなたを引き上げているのですか？
what is it if you hadn't made that
もしあなたがそれを作っていなければ、それは何ですか？
commitment to Christ yet what is it
キリストへのコミットメントは何ですか？
that's stopping you
それはあなたを止めている
and yet you've tuned into our show and
まだあなたは私たちのショーと
you're listening and we are very
あなたは聞いていて、私たちはとてもです
thankful for that but we just pray right
それに感謝していますが、 ただ祈っています
now that God's grace would just go
今、神の恵みはちょうど行くだろう
before touching your heart and if you
あなたの心に触れる前に
have a question if you've been calling
あなたが電話していれば質問があります
out to God then we ask in the name of
神に出てから、私たちは
Jesus that he would just make himself
イエス・キリストは自分自身を作るだけです
real to you even now and that your life
今でもあなたに本当の、そしてあなたの人生
would be changed and you would say I
変更されると私は言うだろう
believe the Bible is very clear it says
聖書は非常に明確であると信じています
if you confess with your mouth Jesus is
あなたの口に告白するなら、イエスは
Lord and believe in your heart that he
主よ、あなたの心を信じてください
raised that God raised him from the dead
神が彼を死から育てたと訴えた
you will be saved and so we pray that
あなたが救われるので、私たちはそれを祈ります
for you today we pray that you would
今日あなたのために、あなたが
confess her with your mouth that Jesus
あなたの口に彼女を告白するイエス
Christ is Lord and believe in your heart
キリストは主であり、あなたの心を信じる
that God raised him from the dead that
神は彼を死から育てた
you wouldn't be like these people who
あなたは これらの 人々の ように はなりません
are willfully choosing not to believe
慎重に信じないことを選んでいる
that something actually did happen to
実際に何かが起こった
may you believe today and we look
あなたは今日信じて、私たちは見えますか？
forward to seeing you next week on new
来週は新しい
everyday TV things so much 14
毎日のテレビのこと14
catch it
それを捕まえて